Finding Aid for the Alfred Leland Crabb Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Writings III
  - The Novel of the Past Historical or Hysterical (Box 24, Folder 18)
  - Preserver Of A Shrine (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - Got Better Going Across (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - The Immanuel Baptist Church (Box 24, Folder 19)
  - A Pleasing Journey (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - A Crook & Some Coincidences (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Hard To Please (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - Religion in the United States (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - No Congregation (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - The Miracle (Box 24, Folder 20)
  - The Funeral (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Tobacco for Soldiers (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - The Softening Of Mr. Reub Simons (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Andrew Jackson Reads the Declaration (Box 24, Folder 21)
  - Meaningful It Isn’t (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Redevelopment of Standards in Teachers Colleges (Box 24, Folder 22)
  - Sunshine Can Warm A Life (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - Cofounder of the Hermitage (Box 24, Folder 23)
  - All Things Begin At Home (Box 24, Folder 24)
  - My Old Kentucky Home (Box 24, Folder 24)
- Writing IV
  - Suburb To Athens (Part I) (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - Suburb To Athens (Part II) (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Nashville: The Suburb City(Part 1) (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Nashville: The Suburb City (Part 2) (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Thankful For A Name (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Twilight Of The Nashville Gods (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - All Things Begin At Home. (Box 25, Folder 8)
  - All Things Begin At Home. (Box 25, Folder 9)
  - Cofounder of the Hermitage. (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Moral Responsibility of Education in the December Ahead. (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Miscellaneous Stories. (Box 25, Folder 12)
- Writings V
  - Suburb to the Hermitage (Part I). (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Suburb to the Hermitage (Part II). (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Suburb to the Hermitage (Part III). (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Suburb to the Hermitage (Part IV). (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Suburb to Athens. (Part III) (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (Part I) (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (Part II) (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (Part III) (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Home to Kentucky (Part II) (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Peace at Bowling Green.(Part I) (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Peace at Bowling Green.(Part II) (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Peace at Bowling Green.(Part III) (Box 26, Folder 12)
- Writings VI
  - Newspaper Clippings (1861) (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Southern Association (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - The Baptists In Nashville (Part I) (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - The Baptists In Nashville (Part II) (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Newspaper Comments On Crabb (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - War Diary Of Chaplain Charles Todd (Latin Bishop) (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - List of Governors (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Leadership In Nashville (Box 27, Folder 8)
  - Writings By Others: Thomas Jefferson (Box 27, Folder 9)
  - Writings: Major Course In Education Of Teachers, (1943) (Box 27, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Others: Educational Philosophy by William T. Harris as Observed in the Peabody Demonstration School. (Box 27, Folder 11)
  - Writings by Others: Influence of Thomas Jefferson as Manifested in the Peabody Demonstration School (Box 27, Folder 12)
  - Indiana State Teachers College Diamond Jubilee, 1945 (Box 27, Folder 13)
  - Writings by Others: Research in the History of Southern Education (Box 27, Folder 14)
  - Writings on Education (Box 27, Folder 15)
  - Bureau of Education Material (Box 27, Folder 16)
  - Alumina Bulletin of University Of Virginia (Box 27, Folder 17)
- Writings Bibliography
  - Bibliography (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Bibliography (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Bibliography (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - A. L. Crabb Book Reviews (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Writings by Others: Alfred Leland Crabb: Educator Novelist (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Writings by Others: Works of Alfred Leland Crabb (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - William Hayes Ackland Papers & Letters Concerning Old Families (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Writings by Others: The Nashville Bible School (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Writings by Others: Thomas Jefferson On Education (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Writings by Others: 10 Outstanding Educators (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - George Washington (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Teachings (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Relationship of Math & Science Education and The Humanities (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Writings by Others: Study Of Francis Bacon & His Influence On The Peabody Demonstration School (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Writings by Others: Influence of Martin Luther on Peabody Demonstration (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - (Box 28, Folder 17)
- Book Draft Manuscripts
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 6-51) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 52-97) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 98-130) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 131-163) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 164-196) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 197-223) (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Pg. 224-262) (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Final Introduction) (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Corrections) (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Introduction) (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Publicity for Peabody and A. L. Crabb (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 1-32) (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 33-111) (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 112-194) (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 195-344) (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 345-396) (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 397-374) (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 108-297) (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Pg. 1-32) (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Peace at Bowling Green Manuscript. (Box 29, Folder 20)
- Book Draft Manuscripts I
  - Medium Well Done (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Home Demonstration Marketing (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (First Draft) 1 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (First Draft) 2 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (First Draft) 3 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (First Draft) 4 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (First Draft) 5 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - A Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (First Draft) 6 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - George Peabody (Initial Draft)1 (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - George Peabody (Initial Draft)2 (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - George Peabody (Initial Draft)3 (Box 30, Folder 12)
- Book Draft Manuscripts II
  - George Peabody (1) (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - George Peabody (2) (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - George Peabody (3) (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - George Peabody (4) (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - George Peabody (5) (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - George Peabody (6) (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Florence Williamson Work (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Inventory Catalogue, 1875 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Vanderbilt University Press Letters (Box 31, Folder 9)
  - Examination of Documents (Box 31, Folder 10)
- Book Draft Manuscripts III
  - Home To Tennessee (1) (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Home To Tennessee (2) (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Home To Tennessee (3) (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Home To Tennessee (4) (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Home To Hermitage, Journey To Nashville (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Home To Kentucky (1) (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Home To Kentucky (2) (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Home To Kentucky (3) (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Home To Kentucky (4) (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Home To Kentucky (5) (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Home To Kentucky (6) (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Special Clippings and Pictures of A. L. Crabb (Box 32, Folder 12)
- Book Draft Manuscripts IV
  - George Peabody (1) (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - George Peabody (2) (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - George Peabody (3) (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - George Peabody (4) (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - George Peabody (5) (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - George Peabody (6) (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Breakfast at the Hermitage (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Breakfast at the Hermitage (Drafts) (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Lodging at the Saint Cloud (First Print Book) (Box 33, Folder 9)
- Book Draft Manuscripts V
  - Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (Part Manuscript) (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Broadcasting Materials (1) (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Broadcasting Materials (2) (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga(1) (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (2) (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Dinner at Belmont (1) (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Dinner at Belmont (2) (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Dinner at Belmont (3) (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Personal Mixed Papers (A. L. Crabb 1) (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Personal Mixed Papers (A. L. Crabb 2) (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Personal Mixed Papers (A. L. Crabb 3) (Box 34, Folder 11)
- Book Draft Manuscripts VI
  - Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Peace at Bowling Green(Work on chapter II and II) (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Peace at Bowling Green (Work on chapter III) (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Peace at Bowling Green Initial Draft (Part III) (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Peace at Bowling Green Initial Draft (Part II) (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Peace at Bowling Green Initial Draft (Part I) (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Manuscript: Peace at Bowling Green (Box 35, Folder 7)
- Mixed Manuscripts
  - Home to Tennessee (1) (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Home to Tennessee (2) (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Home to Tennessee (3) (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Home to Tennessee (4) (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Home to Tennessee (5) (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript: Footnotes in the book. (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Medium Well Done. (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - All Things Begin at Home. (Box 36, Folder 8)
- Final Manuscripts
  - Memberships: Peabody Book Club. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Breakfast at the Hermitage (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Breakfast at the Hermitage (Final Draft) (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Alfred Leland Crabb Educator/Novelist (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Home to the Hermitage (Box 37, Folder 5)
- Final Manuscripts I
  - Letters: Home to the Hermitage (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - The Spirit Maketh Alive (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Short Writings (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Medium Well Done (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Your Great Grandparents Were There (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Suburb of Athens (Box 38, Folder 6)
- Final Manuscripts II
  - Peabody Guest Book (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Dinner at Belmont (Volume II Letters) (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Supper at the Maxwell House (Volume I Letters) (Box 39, Folder 3)
- Final Manuscripts III
  - Manuscript: Reunion at Chattanooga (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga Manuscripts and Notes (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Mockingbird Sang at Chickamauga Manuscripts and Notes (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Suburb to the Hermitage Part VI (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Suburb to the Hermitage Part V (Box 40, Folder 5)
- Final Manuscripts IV
  - Home to Tennessee (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Home To Tennessee (Condensed version) (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - All Things Begin at Home (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Are You Planning to Write a Forever Book? (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts (1) (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous manuscripts (2) (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - News clippings on A. L. Crabb (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - All Things Begin At Home (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Western Journey (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - I Will Prove These With Mirth (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - The Whirlpool Is A Southern Bird (Box 41, Folder 8)
- Manuscripts
  - Teachers College Of The Air Script for broadcast (1) (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Teachers College Of The Air Script for broadcast (2) (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Teachers College Of The Air Script for broadcast (3) (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - They Slept with Their Shoes on (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - Mixed manuscripts (1) (Box 42, Folder 5)
  - Mixed manuscripts (2) (Box 42, Folder 6)
  - Mixed manuscripts (3) (Box 42, Folder 7)
  - Mixed manuscripts (4) (Box 42, Folder 8)
  - Mixed manuscripts (5) (Box 42, Folder 9)
  - Mixed manuscripts (6) (Box 42, Folder 10)
- Manuscripts-Handwritten
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 29-55) (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 64-107) (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 110-127) (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 141-155) (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 196-209) (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 219-243) (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 246-275) (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 277-300) (Box 43, Folder 8)
  - Reunion at Chattanooga (p. 158-182) (Box 43, Folder 9)
  - Manuscripts(1) (Box 43, Folder 10)
  - Manuscripts (2) (Box 43, Folder 11)
  - Manuscripts (3) (Box 43, Folder 12)
  - Manuscripts (4) (Box 43, Folder 13)
  - Writing-Personal notes (Box 43, Folder 14)
- Poetry and Verse
  - Poetry and Verse (1) (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Poetry and Verse (2) (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Poetry and Verse (3) (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Poetry and Verse (4) (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Poetry and Verse (5) (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - Poetry and Verse (6) (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Poetry and Verse (7) (Box 44, Folder 7)
- Research on Southern Life (1)
  - Farm Magazines of The South (Box 45, Folder 1)
  - An Old Fashioned Methodist Camp Meeting (Box 45, Folder 2)
  - Journalism in the South (Box 45, Folder 3)
  - Jews In the Early South (Box 45, Folder 4)
  - Crafts of the Southern Highlands and Poems (Box 45, Folder 5)
  - Southern Fiction Between, 1865-1920 (Box 45, Folder 6)
  - Experiments for Better Living (Box 45, Folder 7)
  - Folk Music (Box 45, Folder 8)
  - Study on Georgia (Box 45, Folder 9)
  - Handicrafts Tennessee (Box 45, Folder 10)
  - The Grand Ole Opry (Box 45, Folder 11)
  - Franklin County Tennessee (Box 45, Folder 12)
  - Folklore Radio Scripts (Box 45, Folder 13)
  - Southern Fiction (Box 45, Folder 14)
  - Bibliography of Novels About Georgia (Box 45, Folder 15)
  - Georgia Writers (Box 45, Folder 16)
  - Georgia Fiction (Box 45, Folder 17)
- Research on Southern Life (2)
  - Economics of the south, (1940) (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Historic homes of Nashville (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Education in the south (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - English 493: Virginia and Mayfield (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Natchez (Where the old south still lives) (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Southern life and culture (Box 46, Folder 6)
  - English in colleges (Box 46, Folder 7)
  - Handicrafts of the southern highlands (Box 46, Folder 8)
  - Universities of Louisville ceremonies (Box 46, Folder 9)
  - The Nashville theatre (Box 46, Folder 10)
  - Dyess colony (Box 46, Folder 11)
  - The drama in southern Universities & Colleges (Box 46, Folder 12)
  - Southern literary culture (Box 46, Folder 13)
  - The dance in southern universities and colleges (Box 46, Folder 14)
  - Delta cooperative farm (Box 46, Folder 15)
  - Mosaic in JFK Human Development Laboratory (Ben Shahn) (Box 46, Folder 16)
  - Books authored (Box 46, Folder 17)
  - Peabody and Alfred Leland Crabb (Box 46, Folder 18)
  - Peabody Reflector items (Box 46, Folder 19)
- Research on Southern Life (3)
  - Cotton (Box 47, Folder 1)
  - Southern Cooking (Box 47, Folder 2)
  - Lost Coins Of the Confederacy (Box 47, Folder 3)
  - Churches of the South (Box 47, Folder 4)
  - Industry in the South (1) (Box 47, Folder 5)
  - Industry in the South (2) (Box 47, Folder 6)
  - Folklore and Education (Box 47, Folder 7)
  - Folklore (Box 47, Folder 8)
  - Southern Foods (Box 47, Folder 9)
  - Marshall Keeble & the Nashville Christian Institute (Box 47, Folder 10)
  - Study on Florida (Box 47, Folder 11)
  - Folk Drama (Box 47, Folder 12)
  - Fisk University Work (Box 47, Folder 13)
- Research on Southern Life (4)
  - Charles Thomas Davis (Box 48, Folder 1)
  - Parasitism as a Southern Problem (Box 48, Folder 2)
  - Sewanee Review (Box 48, Folder 3)
  - Social Experiments in the South (Box 48, Folder 4)
  - Religions of the South (Box 48, Folder 5)
  - Southern Magazines (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Magazine Articles on the South (Box 48, Folder 7)
  - Writings: The Melungeon of Battle Creek (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Life in Louisiana (Box 48, Folder 9)
  - Literary Map of the South (Box 48, Folder 10)
  - Libraries in the South (Box 48, Folder 11)
  - Life in Kentucky (Box 48, Folder 12)
  - Writings: North Carolina Since 1900’s (Box 48, Folder 13)
  - Negro in Southern Literature (Box 48, Folder 14)
  - Segregation in Institutions for Higher Learning (Box 48, Folder 15)
  - Negro Education in Alabama (Box 48, Folder 16)
  - The Negro Artist (Box 48, Folder 17)
  - Mississippi Artists & Musicians (Box 48, Folder 18)
- Research on Southern Life (5)
  - Flowers of the South (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - Kentucky State Teachers College of Bowling Green (Picture of 1962 Class) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Personal Letters To A. L. Crabb (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - Railroad Personalities Of The South (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Writings And Speeches By Dr. Crabb (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Life in Kentucky (1940-1960) (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Nashville Through The Decades (1930-1980) (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - State Parks (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Southern Women Novelists Of The Early Twentieth & Late Nineteenth Century (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Southern Speech (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Units Of Study (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - John Scopes Trial (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Bibliography of the Tennessee Valley Authority, (1936-1938) (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Youth Studies of the South (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - Research into Nashville (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Research on Families (Box 49, Folder 16)
- Research on Southern Life (6)
  - Miscellaneous Writings (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Life In The Coal Mining Camps Of South West Virginia (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Published Writings in Magazines and Journals (1) (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Published Writings in Magazines and Journals (2) (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Published Writings in Magazines and Journals (3) (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Published Writings in Magazines and Journals (4) (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Published Writings in Magazines and Journals (5) (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Published Writings in Magazines and Journals (6) (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Research on Southern Life (7)
  - Art Music In The South (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Archibald Rutledge (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - A Study Of Alabama (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - The Senators From Alabama: Lister Hill & John Sparkman (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - A Study Of Alabama (2) (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - Historic Homes Of The Old South: Brief History Of Virginia Architecture (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - A Study of Arkansas (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - A Study of Arkansas (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Additional Bibliography (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Bibliography on Articles on Southern Literature (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Art in the South (Box 51, Folder 11)
- Research on Southern Life (8)
  - Study on Oklahoma (Box 52, Folder 1)
  - Pulitzer Prize Winners of the South (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Bibliography Mississippi (Box 52, Folder 3)
  - Ruritan National (Box 52, Folder 4)
  - Study on Missouri (Box 52, Folder 5)
  - Southern Life & Literature (Box 52, Folder 6)
  - Scientists of the Old South (Box 52, Folder 7)
  - Sociology (Box 52, Folder 8)
  - Soil Erosion in the South (Box 52, Folder 9)
  - Notes on the South Carolina (Box 52, Folder 10)
  - Religion in the South (Box 52, Folder 11)
  - Southern Festivals and Celebrations (Box 52, Folder 12)
  - Notes on Nashville (Box 52, Folder 13)
  - States of America (Box 52, Folder 14)
  - Notes on Tennessee (Box 52, Folder 15)
  - Alabama Women’s College (1) (Box 52, Folder 16)
  - Alabama Women’s College (2) (Box 52, Folder 17)
  - University Foundations of America (Box 52, Folder 18)
  - Southern Musicians (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - The Memory: An Autobiographical Sketch (Box 52, Folder 20)
  - Cumberland Presbyterian Church (Box 52, Folder 21)
  - Poem & Music by Lizette Reese (Box 52, Folder 22)
- Research on Southern Life (9)
  - Poetry Song Book (Box 53, Folder 1)
  - Biographical Sketches with Southern Novelists (Box 53, Folder 2)
  - Research in Nashville (Box 53, Folder 3)
  - Natchez (Box 53, Folder 4)
  - World Outlook, (November 1939) (Box 53, Folder 5)
  - Life of the Negro, (1949) (Box 53, Folder 6)
  - Methods Employed in Catalogue Presentations (Box 53, Folder 7)
  - Southern Playwrights & Plays (Box 53, Folder 8)
  - Personal Notes (Box 53, Folder 9)
  - The Better Home & Family Life Program of Obion County (Box 53, Folder 10)
  - Reading Adventures in Tennessee (Box 53, Folder 11)
  - The Home in Kentucky (Box 53, Folder 12)
  - Way of Life in Tennessee During Mid-Twentieth Century (Box 53, Folder 13)
  - Poem Cards (Box 53, Folder 14)
  - State Songs Of The South (Box 53, Folder 15)
  - Southern Actors. (Box 53, Folder 16)
  - Letters to A. L. Crabb (Printing) (Box 53, Folder 17)
  - News Clippings on A. L. Crabb (Box 53, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence & Letters (Box 53, Folder 19)
  - Southern Church Music (Box 53, Folder 20)
  - Southern Oratory (Box 53, Folder 21)
  - Poems of the Southern Confederacy (Box 53, Folder 22)
- Works On Teaching
  - Work with Words (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - Thar’s Gold in Thar Hills (Box 54, Folder 2)
  - The White Pilgrim (Box 54, Folder 3)
  - Words Can Betray You (Box 54, Folder 4)
  - Catholic Church & the Social Problem (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - Chart of American History and Southern Culture (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - Notes on Teaching English (Box 54, Folder 7)
  - The Abraham Lincoln Quarterly, 1952 (Box 54, Folder 8)
  - Tennessee Historical Quarterly (Box 54, Folder 9)
  - Peabody Publications (Box 54, Folder 10)
  - Distinguished Alumni University of Kentucky. (Box 54, Folder 11)
  - Teachers College Of The Air Script For Broadcast (Box 54, Folder 12)
  - Exercises In English (Box 54, Folder 13)
  - American Bar Association, 1948 (Box 54, Folder 14)
  - Thomas Jefferson, 1749-1943 (Box 54, Folder 15)
  - Peabody Publications (Box 54, Folder 16)
- Short Stories and Poems
  - News Extract On A. L. Crabb (1) (Box 55, Folder 1)
  - News Extract On A. L. Crabb (2) (Box 55, Folder 2)
  - Short Stories And Poems (1) (Box 55, Folder 3)
  - Short Stories And Poems (2) (Box 55, Folder 4)
  - Short Stories And Poems (3) (Box 55, Folder 5)
  - Short Stories And Poems (4) (Box 55, Folder 6)
  - Short Stories And Poems (5) (Box 55, Folder 7)
  - Short Stories And Poems (6) (Box 55, Folder 8)
  - Address By A. L. Crabb (Dedication Of Memorial Entranceway Western Kentucky State College) (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Articles about Peabody College
  - Peabody articles 1930 (Part 1) (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - Peabody articles 1930 (Part 2) (Box 56, Folder 2)
  - Peabody articles 1930 (Part 3) (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - The story of Peabody (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Story of Peabody as Revealed in Writings of A. L. Crabb (Part 1) (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Story of Peabody as Revealed in Writings of A. L. Crabb (Part 2) (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Story of Peabody as Revealed in Writings of A. L. Crabb (Part 3) (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - Peabody and Alfred Leland Crabb (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Peabody Reflector, (Fall 1971) (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Peabody Articles, (1943-1950) (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - Peabody Articles, (1954-1975) (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - Peabody Articles, (1930-1941) (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - Teachers College Turns Professional (Box 56, Folder 13)
- Peabody College Publications.
  - Peabody Reflector (1) (Box 57, Folder 1)
  - Peabody Reflector (2) (Box 57, Folder 2)
  - Peabody Reflector (3) (Box 57, Folder 3)
  - Peabody Reflector (4) (Box 57, Folder 4)
  - Peabody Reflector (5) (Box 57, Folder 5)
  - Peabody Publications (Box 57, Folder 6)
- Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1930-1970)
  - Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1936-1937) (Box 58, Folder 1)
  - Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1937) (Box 58, Folder 2)
  - Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1938) (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1934) (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1940) (Box 58, Folder 5)
  - Peabody Reflector Extracts, (1939) (Box 58, Folder 6)